Guide to the Chris Kraus collection of Kathy Acker papers, 1971-2017 RL.11745
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Chris Kraus collection of Kathy Acker papers
1971-2017 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kraus, Chris
RL.11745
17 Linear Feet
Chris Kraus is a writer and filmmaker who is also the co-editor of the press Semiotext(e). In 2017, she published After Kathy Acker: A Literary Biography (Semiotext(e), 2017). This collection is comprised of the materials she created or amassed in the process of writing that book.
Arrangement
Materials in the series "After Kathy Acker Book Chapters" are arranged into nine subseries corresponding to the chapters in Kraus' book After Acker: A Literary Biography with the exception of "Littoral Madness" as well as drafts, typescripts, footnotes, legends, and style sheets of the whole book. The other series in the collection include "Background Material" collected by Kraus in support of her book, "Financial Records" accumulated and organized by Kathy Acker into labeled envelopes, "Printed Material," "Audiovisual Material and Electronic Records." Kraus' original folder titles have been preserved in most cases.
Biographical / Historical
Chris Kraus is a writer and filmmaker. Before beginning her career as writer, Kraus made a number of short films and videos, including one feature, Gravity & Grace. She is the author of four novels, including I Love Dick, Aliens & Anorexia, Torpor, and Summer of Hate as well as collected essays on art. She is co-editor of the press Semiotext(e), where she started their Native Agents series. She was a 2016 Guggenheim Fellow, and teaches at the Art Center in Pasadena, CA. In 2017 she published After Kathy Acker: A Literary Biography. Her novel I Love Dick was adapted as a television series by Jill Soloway.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Chris Kraus Collection of Kathy Acker papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2019.
Related Materials
Kathy Acker papers
Collection Overview
The Chris Kraus Collection of Kathy Acker papers is comprised of materials Kraus created or amassed in the process of writing her biography of Kathy Acker, After Kathy Acker: A Literary Biography (Semiotext(e), 2017). The collection includes emails between Kraus and Acker's friends and colleagues; copies of manuscript material (primarily letters) from Acker gathered by Kraus from research libraries and private collections (very few of which duplicate materials in the Kathy Acker papers held by Duke); audio recordings of interviews between Kraus and Acker's associates, accompanied by transcriptions; Kraus's research notes, compiled quotes, and other research materials; collected press and reviews of Acker's work; typescripts and published works by and about Acker; Acker's financial records pertaining to expenditures, earnings, inheritances, and real estate; chapter drafts of Kraus's book; and a small amount of print ephemera and original photographs.
Interviewees and correspondents include: Lynne Tillman, Dennis Cooper, Gary Pulsifer, Amy Scholder, Neil Gaiman, Janey Smith, Dodie Bellamy, Robert Gluck, Stuart Home, P. Adams Sitney, Alan Sondheim, Eleanor Antin, Martha Rosler, and many others.
Acker, Kathy, 1948-1997; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- After Kathy Acker Book Chapters, 1975-2016 and undated
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in the first eight boxes include research files, interviews, correspondence, chapter drafts and other materials related to all of the chapters in After Kathy Acker: A Literary Biography except the first chapter of that book, "Littoral Madness." The final box in this series includes typescripts for all chapters plus style sheets, footnotes and related material.
  - Politics, undated
    - Len Neufeld (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Matha Rosler (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Brandeis (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Politics by KA (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Lenox School: Lenox Lantern (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Lenox School: High School Dating (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Lenox School: Elizabeth Benedict on Lenox (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lenox School: P. Adams Sitney (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Julien Raffinot (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lenox School: Yearbook Information (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Sex Show (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - KA to Rothenberg letters, diary (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - W 163rd (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bernadette Mayer - Memory (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Handwritten Notes by Chris Kraus on KA (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - St. Marks Poetry Project (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Politics (chapter versions) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula, 1998-2016 and undated
    - TBT compoisition (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Close Readings (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mel Frielicher on KA, 1998-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Eleanor and David Antin, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Jackson MacLow (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Rothenberg, MacLow (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Rothenberg, Neufeld (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - I dreamed.... (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Robert Ashley (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Homage to LeRoi Jones (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Acker to Bernadette (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Larry McCaffrey Interview (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Final Footnoted chapter (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Research Material, 2016 and undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Breaking Through Memories into Desire, 1974-2000 and undated
    - The Blue Tape (VHS tape), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Essay by CK: Sex, Truths, and Videotape, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Anna Maria Pinaka (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Alan Sondheim Autobiographical Text (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Blue Tape Transcript (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Acker to A. Sondheim, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Email between CK and A. Sondheim (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Nymphomanic Alphabet, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Robert Smithson (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Antin Ballerina (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Letters from Other Writers (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Breaking Through (footnoted chapter draft) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Breaking Through (final chapter draft) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Research Material (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Tasting and Spitting, 1975-2016 and undated
    - Rudy Wurlitzer correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Blood and Guts - Quotes from (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hank Bull (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Constance DeJong (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Judith Doyle (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Peter Gordon (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Dan Graham (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Leandro Katz (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Jill Kroesen (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Robert Kushner (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lil Picard (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Ron Silliman (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Barbara Caspar Documentary (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Readings of KA (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Tasting and Spitting Footnoted (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - NYC 1975, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Barry Alpert - KA Interview, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Tasting and Spitting (chapter versions), 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
    - Research Material, 1988, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Person of Great Expectations, 1977-2015 and undated
    - Piece by KA in RE/Search, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Paul Buck, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Terrence Sellers (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Jeff Goldberg (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - James Grauerholz (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Michael Roloff (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Pooh Kaye (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - George Quasha (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Reading Graphs (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Apartments (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Probate: Albert Alexander, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Probate: Claire Alexander, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Probate: Florence Weill, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Laure (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Biographies (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Jonathan Miles, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Luc Sante, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Seattle, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Great Expectations (notes) (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Great Expectations (chapter drafts), 3 folders (Box 5, Folder 20-22)
    - Great Expectations (chapter correspondence and research) (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Fiction, 1983-1991 and undated
    - 39 E 12th Purchase (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Dead Doll (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Coverage, 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Coverage, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - KA Interviews, 1985-1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - KA Art Writing, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - William Gibson (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Darius James (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Harold Robbins (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Reviews of KA books (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Jaqui Graham (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Nathalie de Broglio (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Riverview Gardens, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Late London BDSM, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - London Notebook (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Roz Kaveney (Box 6, Folder 16)
      General
      Contains mini cassette
    - Fred Jordan (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Peter Wollen, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - South Bank Show (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Barry Miles (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Michael Bracewell (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Melissa Benn (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Fiction (chapter drafts) (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Research Materials (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 1995, 1990-1996
    - Very Into You (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Competition NYC (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Falkner to Acker 1992 Summer (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 90s cyberpunk interests (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - New Statesman Killed 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Acker Corkboard (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 90s career burnout (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Acker to Cooper (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Acker to Tillman (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Pantheon (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Larry McCaffery Interview, April 1990 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Coverage, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - KA to Grove Press, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Portrait of an Eye reviews (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - NYC, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1992 Reviews (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Demonology, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Book Reviews, 1993, 1996; 2 folders (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
    - Amy Scholder (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Gary Pulsifer to Acker, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Ira Silverberg - Fales (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Lynne Tillman (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - RU Sirious (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - KA Interview, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Mekons (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Reviews of Anthologies KA is in (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Acker in OED, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - KA Memorial London (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Pussy - publicity including Jessica Berens (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Spice Girls Response (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - London, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - KA - Clothes (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - KA: Review of Features by (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Review of Eurydice (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Bodies of Work Reviews (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Gift of disease response (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - KA Obits - UK Press and Responses (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Poem, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - KA Residence: 39 E 12th St. Apt. 11 NY, NY 10012 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Janine Herman interview (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Ken Jordan interview (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Janey Smith (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Roz Kaveney (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Neil Gaiman (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - San Francisco Art Institute (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Research materials (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Fable, undated
    - Beautiful Death (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Blancornelas (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mastectomy (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sylvere Lotringer (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Matias Viegener (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Who's afraid of KA, Barlona Caspar (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Chris Kraus published pieces on KA (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Biomedica/American Biologics (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Tijuana Juan Soldado (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Charles Murray Obituary (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Memorial Notes (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Eleanor and David Antin (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Gift of Disease (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - After Kathy Acker drafts, 1995 and undated
    - After Kathy Acker Style Sheet (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Littoral Madness (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Politics: drafts (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula: drafts (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Breaking through Memories into Desire (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Tasting and Spitting: draft (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - A Person of Great Expectations: draft (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Fiction: draft (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1995: draft (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Fable: draft (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - After Kathy Acker: A Critical Biography (annotated typescript), 2 folders (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
    - The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula: A 20th Century Fable (typescript) (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - After Kathy Acker: A Critical Biography (legend and footnotes) (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Acker Background Material, 1971-2017 and undated
  Materials in this series include research and subject files documenting Kathy Acker's life and work amassed in the process of writing Kraus's book, After Kathy Acker: A Literary Biography but that are not associated with specific chapters as the material in the first series of this collection are.
  - Bob Acker (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Dodie Bellamy (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Kaucyila Brooke (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bob Gluck (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Stuart Home, Ravens Row, London (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Gary Indiana (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - P. Adams Sitney (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Janey Smith (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Jeff Wright (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Timelines of KA's Life (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Algeria (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - CK Published Pieces on KA (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Michelle Handelman (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - KA Diaries, 1971; 2 folders (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - Research Materials (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Salman Rushdie (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Ira Silverberg emails, 1990s; 5 folders (Box 11, Folder 2-6)
  - Chris Kraus interview with Jarrett Earnest (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Ka Obituary (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Chris to Maxine, 2017 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - CK Handwritten Notes (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - CK's Corkboard (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Lewis Warsh and Anne Waldman, 2017 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Eileen Myles, 2017 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - KA Diary NY 1971 (photocopy) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Acker Correspondence to McKenzie Wark, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - KA Correspondence, 1971-1997; 3 folders (Box 12, Folder 6-8)
  - The Complete Works of Constance (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Acker's Great Expectations (early draft) (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Notebooks, Photocopied, of KA, 2 folders (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
  - Fundraising (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Research Material (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - KA's Bulletin Board (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Variety (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - One World (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - KA Obituaries (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - NYC in 1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - KA Chapbook, Paul Buck, London, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - SF Memorial, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - UCSD History (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - UCSD Archive (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - KA at War with Poets (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - KA: Birth of the Poet (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Lust: 7 Deadly Sins (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - KA Proposal Drafts (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Chris Kraus and Sylvere Lotringer (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - KA Clothes (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - UK Pictures (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - When She Does What She Does (Douglas A. Martin typescript) (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - KA: Implosion (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Blood and Guts Publication History (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Hannibal Lecter Interview (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Chris Kraus: Early Attempts to Write About Kathy Acker (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Photos of Acker's Address (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Financial Records, undated
  Records documenting Kathy Acker's expenditures, earnings, banking, and taxes as compiled into labeled envelopes by Acker herself. Acker's organization, including labeled envelopes, has been maintained.
  - Books (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Business Meals (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Charity (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Chicago Trip (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Citibank and Taxes (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Clothes (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Food (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - House - San Francisco (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Health (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Medical and Other (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - NYC Apartment (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - NYC Trip to See Publisher and Agent (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Other and Cash (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Reading at Dartmouth College (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Records (Music) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Transportation (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Trip to Alfred Reading and Class (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Trip to London and Brighton (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Tour for Australia (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Tour Expenses, Leila Wallace (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Travel (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Work (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Envelopes (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Banking, 2 folders (Box 14, Folder 24-25)
  - Earnings and Royalty Statements (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Receipts (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Taxes (Box 14, Folder 28)
- Printed Materials, 1975-2015
  This series includes copies of Kathy Acker's publications including rare small press and periodical publications as well as publications about Acker. Also included are a small number of publications by others not directly related to Kathy Acker.
  - Publications by Kathy Acker
    - Rip-Off Red, Girl Detective and The Burning Bombing of America, Grove Press, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Literal Madness (Kathy Goes to Haiti, My Death My Life by Pier Paolo Pasolini, Florida), Grove Press, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Great Expectations, Grove Press, 1982; 2 copies (Box 15)
    - Blood and Guts in High School, 1978; 2 copies Copies have different covers (Box 15)
    - Blood and Guts in High School Plus Two, Picador, 1983 (Box 15)
    - The Persian Poems of Janey Smith (excerpted from Blood and Guts in High School), Bozeau of London Press, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Don Quixote, Grove Press, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Empire of the Senseless, Grove Press, 1988 (Box 15)
    - In Memoriam to Identity, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Hannibal Lecter, My Father, Semiotext(e), 1991 (Box 15)
    - Portrait of an Eye (three novels: The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula, I Dreamt I Became A Nymphomaniac: Imagining, and The Adult Life of Tolouse-Lautrec), Grove Press, 1992 (Box 15)
    - My Mother: Demonology, Pantheon Books, 1993 (Box 15)
    - Pussy, King of the Pirates, Grove Press, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Eurydice in the Underworld, Arcadia Books, 1997 (Box 15)
    - Bodies of Work, essays, Serpent's Tail, 1997 (Box 15)
    - Tales from San Francisco Coke! Stooge #13, 1975 (Box 15)
    - Unmuzzled Ox, vol. 4, no 4/vol. 5: Slavery (an entry by Kathy Acker in the Poet's Encyclopedia, p, 250-252, 1979 (Box 15)
    - New York City in 1979, Crawl out of Your Window, 7, July, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Interview with Kathy Acker, Crawl out of Your Window #17, September, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Homage to Leroi Jones and other Early Works, Lost and Found, The CUNY Poetics Document Initiative, Series 5, Number 1, Spring, 2015 (Box 15)
    - Roman Day (altered newspaper), 1981 (Box 15)
    - Acker: Articles from the New Statesman, 1989-1991, Amandla Publishing, 2007 (Box 15)
    - Spread Wide: An Encounter between Kathy Acker & Paul Bruck with further interventions from Rebecca Stephens and John Cussans, Editions Dis Voir, 2004 (Box 15)
    - Angry Women, Re/Search (interview with Kathy Acker), 1991 (Box 15)
    - Art, Performance, Media: 31 Interviews, University of Minnesota Press (interview with Kathy Acker), 2004 (Box 15)
    - Essential Acker: The Selected Writings of Kathy Acker. Grove Press, 2002 (Box 15)
  - Publications about Kathy Acker
    - Blood and Guts in Hollywood: Two Screenplays by Laura Parnes with an introduction by Chris Kraus, Participant Press, 2009 (Box 15)
    - Lust For Life: On the Writings of Kathy Acker, Verso, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Moran, Joe, Star Authors: Literary Celebrity in America, Pluto Press, 2000 (Box 15)
    - In Memoriam to Identity, Grove Press, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Hannibal Lecter, My Father, Semiotext(e), 1991 (Box 16)
  - Publications by Others
    Removed due to mold: Bockris, Victor. With William Burroughs: A Report From the Bunker, Seaver Books, 1981.
    - Antin, David. I Never Knew What Time Was, University of California Press, 2005 (Box 16)
    - Atkins, Marc and Iain Sinclair, Liquid City, Reaktion Books, 1999 (Box 16)
    - Burroughs, William S. The Place of Dead Roads, Picador, 1983 (Box 16)
    - Robbins, Harold. The Pirate, Pockets Books, 1975 (Box 16)
    - Wilson, Andrew. Harold Robbins: The Man Who Invented Sex, Bloomsbury Publishing, 2007 (Box 16)
    - Wollen, Peter. Readings and Writings: Semiotic Counter-Strategies, Verso Editions, 1982 (Box 16)